

(719)641-6836 lindsey.e.choi@gmail.com

Lindsey Choi

I'm a full stack developer with a passion for creating stream-lined, attractive applications. My focus is on the frontend and UI portions of applications, and I work with business architects as an integral part of a development team to create technical solutions for business needs. I can assist your team in building and maintaining resilient, robust applications that provide flawless user experiences and design for your customers.

SKILLS

Programming Languages - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python

Technology - Angular, React, NgRx, NodeJS, Git, GitHub, Insomnia, Postman, Sandbox, Mongoose, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Heroku, Lighthouse, VS Code, MERN Stack, GraphQL, Webpack, Jenkins, Spring Boot, Maven

Technical Concepts - CI/CD Pipelines, OOP, CRUD, RESTful web services, JSON, API, MVC, Progressive Web Applications, Responsive Design, UX/UI design

Engineering Concepts - Agile Methodology, requirements gathering and analysis, DevOps, software testing, clear and concise technical writing skills

EXPERIENCE

TEKsystems/FedEx, Applications Programmer — FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

September 2022 - PRESENT

- Currently working as a full stack developer with a focus on UI and frontend implementation for internal FedEx applications
- Enterprise level experience frontend/UI work, including Angular and TypeScript
- Utilizing Java and Spring Boot on all backend services
- Working directly with the business architects to deliver applications to meet their needs for manifests, overages, and other reporting systems
- Enterprise level application remediation work with CI pipelines to upgrade security and versioning within existing FedEx applications
- Practiced SAFe Agile in daily standups, sprint planning, retrospectives, and PI planning

2U, Computer Science Grader and Teaching Assistant — FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

AUGUST 2022 - OCTOBER 2022

- Part-time grader and teaching assistant for 2U, helping to bridge the technology gap by providing feedback and instruction to full-stack coding students
- Working as a part of a team to provide technical support
- Utilizing skills as a front-end and back-end developer

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of Denver - Certificate

NOVEMBER 2021 - JUNE 2022

Colorado State University - Bachelor of Arts

AUGUST 2007 - MAY 2011

PROJECTS

Close Encounters, University of Denver Full Stack Bootcamp

JUNE 2022

- JavaScript application that utilizes React
- MongoDB with Mongoose/GraphQL
- Users view paranormal encounters other users have entered into the database via Leaflet map, login and view personal profile
- User can enter their own paranormal encounters via the Leaflet map by dropping a pin and filling out a form

Accretion, University of Denver Full Stack Bootcamp

APRIL 2022

- Javascript application that utilizes MySQL and Sequelize
- Constructed for a client with the United States Geological Survey
- Application accumulates paperwork digitally that employees submit from offices across the country

MY WORK

Portfolio

• View my deployed personal portfolio, powered by React at:

https://lindseychoi.github.io/lindseychoi-portfolio/

GitHub

• Take a look at my other projects at:

https://github.com/lindseychoi

CERTIFICATIONS

- STATE OF COLORADO, PROFESSIONAL TEACHING LICENSE
- Currently studying for COMPTIA SECURITY+ certification, sitting for exam in April 2023